[
{
"question": "Who is the primary villain in the first 'Avengers' movie?",
"options": [
"Loki",
"Thanos",
"Ultron",
"Red Skull"
],
"answer": "Loki",
"explanation": "Loki is the primary villain in the first 'Avengers' movie."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of Tony Stark's personal AI assistant?",
"options": [
"JARVIS",
"FRIDAY",
"ULTRON",
"DUM-E"
],
"answer": "JARVIS",
"explanation": "JARVIS is the name of Tony Stark's personal AI assistant."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the metal that Tony Stark's suit is made of?",
"options": [
"Adamantium",
"Vibranium",
"Palladium",
"Titanium"
],
"answer": "Titanium",
"explanation": "Tony Stark's suit is made of Titanium."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the organization that Nick Fury leads?",
"options": [
"SHIELD",
"HYDRA",
"AIM",
"Alpha Flight"
],
"answer": "SHIELD",
"explanation": "Nick Fury leads SHIELD."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the planet that Thor is from?",
"options": [
"Asgard",
"Vormir",
"Sakaar",
"Knowhere"
],
"answer": "Asgard",
"explanation": "Thor is from Asgard."
},
{
"question": "Who is the leader of the Chitauri army in the first 'Avengers' movie?",
"options": [
"Loki",
"Thanos",
"Ultron",
"The Other"
],
"answer": "The Other",
"explanation": "The leader of the Chitauri army in the first 'Avengers' movie is The Other."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the organization that the Winter Soldier is associated with?",
"options": [
"Hydra",
"Aim",
"Shield",
"Leviathan"
],
"answer": "Hydra",
"explanation": "The Winter Soldier is associated with Hydra."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the superpowered villain played by Michael Keaton in 'Spider-Man: Homecoming'?",
"options": [
"Green Goblin",
"Vulture",
"Doctor Octopus",
"Sandman"
],
"answer": "Vulture",
"explanation": "Michael Keaton played the superpowered villain Vulture in 'Spider-Man: Homecoming'."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the giant green superhero played by Mark Ruffalo in the MCU?",
"options": [
"The Thing",
"The Hulk",
"Colossus",
"Juggernaut"
],
"answer": "The Hulk",
"explanation": "Mark Ruffalo played the giant green superhero The Hulk in the MCU."
},
{
"question": "What is the name of the team of superheroes led by Captain America?",
"options": [
"The Avengers",
"The Defenders",
"The X-Men",
"The Guardians of the Galaxy"
],
"answer": "The Avengers",
"explanation": "The team of superheroes led by Captain America is called The Avengers."
}
  ]
